Thank you for being here.
My name is Zhijing Wang and I am a PhD
student at Nanotechnological University.
Today I present my paper entitled
Reimagining Authorship
in Contemporary Chinese Poetry.
Sorry.
Okay, so
in this exam,
some early experiments in creating
or can incorporating
the technological agencies in writing.
Although the text in these experiments
may appear less sophisticated
than those produced by contemporary
AI system, they inspire a framework
that remains valuable
for interpreting with AI generated stack.
Today.
Sorry.
Okay,
so let's begin with a simple question.
Can read this.
Recognize AI generated poetry.
Although AI has made remarkable
progress in poem generation.
Most study has shown that non-expert
reader can not reliably distinguish
AI generated point from human author one.
But once readers know that
the point is generated,
they tend to evaluate it more negatively.
This raised two question
why has poetry become one of the primary
literary forms
for experimentation in AI text generation?
And why does authorship continue
to shape readers interpretation,
even when they cannot distinguish
the AI generated text from the human
authors? One.
This question
are related to the way of poetry reading.
Firstly, AI text generation align
well with the poetic form
because the poetic meaning image through
possibility relation among the images,
which allows the reader to actively
construct coherence across semantic gaps.
Since AI generated will sequences
through the statistical prediction,
poetry can rely on reader's active
construction of coherence to transform
the probabilistic world association
into meaningful interpretation.
However, the organization of coherence
is generally
based on readers
assumption of a single human author.
As AI becomes increasingly integrated
into literary writing.
Readers are often unable to distinguish
AI generated stack from the human
author's one unless they use of
AI clearly declared by the author.
So despite of this uncertainty, readers
continue to organize textual coherence
as if the point were produced
by an intentional author.
So what motivates the interpretation,
therefore,
is not the author's actual existence,
but the assumption of the authorship
through which readers
organize the poetic form into a whole.
In terms of this, we should ask, that
is politics
only the representation of the authorship?
Or how does the poetry, applying different
technological agents
organize the authorship within the text?
My argument
is that from the hermeneutic perspective,
different political point
can produce multiple forms of authorship.
As technological agents
reshape textual construction,
they give rise to what I call
algorithmic authorship,
which reorganizes the relationship
between the authorship and the meaning.
So what is authorship from perspective?
Authorship has been depicted
as a constructed conception
whose function is to characterize
the existing circulation
and operation
of certain discourse within a society.
Although
the author's name server is a principle
that allows the text to delineate
as if the particular object feature
also argues that the author functions
operates through the variation
between the different self
within the text.
However, compared to the period
that Foucault theorizes the authorship,
the author itself
that ensured purity of self
has been confronted with
the challenge of division is all texts
today are shadowed by the suspicion
of technological involvement,
especially with the emergence of AI
in this regard.
How do we understand the role
of authorship in terms of hermeneutics?
When technological agents
have intervened in texture production?
Firstly, we need to clarify
what technological agents are.
By this term, I define them
as a computational artifact that acts
on behalf of user to make the decision
and actively shape textual output.
I use this term technological agents
as an umbrella conception,
rather than restricting it to AI alone.
Because many of today's AI systems
do not emerge out of nowhere
as if they were alien technologies
that appear suddenly.
In fact, the development of AI has evolved
through multiple stages,
and this system also built on some earlier
technological
agents
that we were already familiar with.
So on the basis of the definition,
I choose three types of work.
Examples.
According to the degree
of technological involvement in the poem
writing, to show the similar ways
of creating the technological authorship
in the contents
of contemporary Chinese poetry.
For the
human author poetry, for example,
in this work, Tongjian portrays
how robots from its subjectivity
while solving the human.
It says happy in the highlighted lines
here, but the word function
only as a placeholder, as a robot
has no experience of being happy
only when it learns to say the word done.
So the happy acquired
meaning through the contrast
and shows the emergence
of a robot subjectivity.
So the idea of robots self conception
is a very common sense of what clinched.
But what I want to emphasize here
is that its subjectivity is constructed
through a distinctly machine
style language.
Although we humans have reached vocabulary
for depicting the emotional experience.
The point
intentionally restricted expression
to simple words, which inspired the reader
to imagine a non-human perspective
through this abnormal vocabularies.
This example highlights
a technological mindset
and a model of expression being radical,
distinct from those of human.
I named this quality as alternatives.
In the philosophy of
Levinas is defined as an absolute order
that demands ethical responsibility,
while either conceptualize technology
as cuisine, other
whose status is between that of of
object and absolute.
After the point example demonstrated
from a literature perspective
how to show that how the otherness
of technology can be represented
in the dual perspective.
On the one hand, it cannot be equal
to human languages semantically happy.
That's not mean happy,
and it must be understood
through the logic of textual construction.
On the other hand, is positioned
within the text, invites reader
to interpret the relationship
and difference
between technological expression
and the narrative.
This alterity is transformed
into the algorithmic
algorithmic authorship
in the example of human technological
collaborative poetry as well.
Penalizing
is a poetry collection by the Taiwanese.
In 2007.
It increased sentences collected online
and repeatedly translated
into Chinese through the machine
translator Sherlock,
whose awkward and grammatical translation
is intentionally preserved,
continue, revise the English source,
and produce bilingual points
that imitate the format
of the translated poetry.
This line presents three versions
of a point from the noisy, and the version
two is Chinese point, and in
Chinese and version three is
is in source text, and the version
one is my English translation
for reference.
The comparison between the version
two and three reviews the significant
differences in language style.
For instance,
the fluent English text become fragmented
and often ungrammatical in Chinese,
whose style is similar to the data
that is the esthetics.
Compared with the previous series work.
Extended linguistic alterity
from abnormal vocabularies
to the level of texture construction,
and clearly lineata,
the robot subjectivity is transformed
into a potential
algorithmic author
within a dual form of authorship.
In this case, it's
difficult to distinguish the technological
contribution from her own
creative intervention and read.
This interpretation
can no longer be attributed to
a single authorial source.
The of the algorithmic author.
Therefore image.
Within this uncertain authorship,
it cannot be reduced
to human intention
but embedded within human language.
It therefore continually demands
readers interpretation,
so we can see that
collaborative writing inevitably involves
the hybridity of authorship.
But what happens
if we remove the human author and
look only at AI generated poetry?
This virtual collection, The Sun Lost
the Glass Window, was generated
by the Microsoft Shell Ice,
which is published its first Chinese
poetry collection in 2017.
Through the model and its work,
compared with the case
where implementation is negotiated
between human intention
and technological intervention.
Readers interpretation of
AI generated state can only be directed
toward the algorithmic itself.
However, through the conventions
of reading, the imagination
of a certain form of subjectivity
is still preserved in the interpretation
of AI generated texts,
which extend the framework of dual
authorship.
For instance,
there were such as the author
authority, War, and you Live,
maybe construct an anti-war context.
So in
conclusion, through these cases,
we can see that poetic form
is not merely a passive representation
of a single authorship.
Through the alterity of the language,
it can actively shape up
the presence
of the alternative mode of authority
through the particular logic
of texture construction.
This politic, found along
well with the technological authority,
is consistently manifest across
different types of work.
It therefore opens up the possibility
of a dual form of authorship,
in which the alternative of languages
shifts the reader's intention
from the semantic content
to the texture construction.
While the presence of technology,
as in other news, also suggests that
the interpretation of the test
can never be fully exhausted.
So the fuller implication
this earlier experiments
provide an interpretative framework
for understanding
that will also shift
in the area of the generative AI.
As I become increasingly embedded
in literature writing,
technological agencies
may become less presented,
but its will continue to challenge
our relationship with the technology.
So this is a reference.
Thank you.